# Lucas Rizoli

lucas@lucasrizoli.com +1 647 520 7887 https://lucasrizoli.com/

An effective User Experience Researcher & Designer with years of experience generating insights and motivating change to better products and processes. Advocate for the users on web, mobile, and in entertainment software projects, small and large; collaborator across disciplines and organizations to achieve success within and without.

# **Selected Experience**

## Design Researcher, RBC (Royal Bank of Canada)

2021 - Present

- Conducted generative and evaluative research of digital banking experiences.
- Generated wireframes and functional prototypes in Figma.
- Worked closely with designers, writers, business analysts, programmers to improve client experiences as well as internal processes and documentation.

## **UX Research Project Manager, Ubisoft Toronto**

2016 - 2020

- Directed UX research for multi-million-dollar software titles *Starlink*: *Battle for Atlas* and *Far Cry 6* in all aspects: needs-gathering, strategy, schedule, budget, methodology, recruitment, and reporting.
- Championed users, working closely with experts, design, art, and production to exceed existing standards. Advocated for accessibility, leading early feature design and requirements.
- Worked with business, marketing, direction, and more to identify goals and opportunities.
- Developed new research methodologies and processes to address stakeholders' needs: generative and evaluative studies, user journeys, narrative tests, wayfinding, testing with children, toy ergonomics.
- Built processes, templates, and documentation to make work clearer, faster, more effective.
- Coached analysts, moderators, and designers on UX, reporting, and usability to improve study and report quality, to communicate clearly, build rapport, manage time and expectations.
- Organized in-depth summary studies and discussions of existing research to address design needs early. Facilitated post-study action on research insights; integrated changing needs into research plans.
- Coordinated UX research and development across many teams in studios across the world.
   Furthered access & understanding of UX research across the organization.

2014 - 2016

#### UX Research Analyst, Ubisoft Toronto

- Conducted over a hundred studies, often from planning, design, recruitment, technical set-up, to analysis and reporting. Produced results with direct and sizable impacts on many products.
- Analyzed and synthesized insights from a variety of qualitative and quantitative data from telemetry, video, eye-tracking, individual and group interviews, questionnaires, and more.
- Ran usability studies, think-aloud, heuristic evaluations, cognitive walkthroughs, card sorts, focus groups, qualitative coding, RITE, appreciation studies and many more.

- Established new and improved standards and tools for reporting, statistical analyses, prioritization, and KPIs. Helped improve research processes with experience, research, coaching, and iteration.
- Trained many across the organization on user-centred design and research processes.
- Worked with developers and production to plan work, further tests, and long-term goals.
- Consulted with designers and researchers to better understand users and their needs, to
  prototype and test iteratively, and to use existing knowledge to maximize effectiveness of
  their work.
- Analyst for more than 25 software titles and franchises for PlayStation/Xbox/Switch, PC, and mobile phones, including Assassin's Creed, Watch Dogs, Far Cry, The Crew, The Division, Super Mario + Rabbids, Ghost Recon, South Park, Care Bears, and various unannounced titles.

2013 - 2014

# Developer/Analyst, Massive Insights

• Prepared, synthesized, visualized, and analyzed large data using Tableau, Excel, and Python.

2012 - 2013

## Web Developer, University of Toronto Scarborough

- Worked with staff, faculty, and students to organize an information architecture to meet institutional and user needs.
- Introduced and integrated new coding practices and tools to better consistency and productivity.

2011 - 2012

# Web & Mobile App Developer, LoyaltyOne

- Designed, developed, and debugged mobile apps from UX to APIs, integrating various teams.
- Researched, experimented, and reported on new technology and practices to make recommendations and determine product strategy.
- Developed websites with HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, PHP, JSP.

#### Education

MSc in Computer Science, University of British Columbia, Vancouver

2006 - 2010

- Thesis project: A multimedia interface for facilitating comparisons of opinions. Published and presented at the International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces, 2009.
- Courses included HCI/UI, Natural Language Processing, Information Visualization, Data Mining, Machine Learning, Scientific Journalism, Semantics (Linguistics), and English Grammar.
- Teaching Assistant for courses on Human–Computer Interaction and Computing Ethics & Society.

BCmp (Honours) in Cognitive Science, Queen's University, Kingston

2002 - 2006

#### **Activities**

- User Research Mentor, IGDA Games Research and User Experience Special Interest Group
- Co-founder of both Undistinguished Lecture Series at UBC and Perch Lecture Group (Toronto)
- Clear, capable, and confident speaker.